孩子们  都坐得舒服吗?
Now, children, are you sitting comfortably?
我开始了
Then I'll begin.
故事始于几千年前
This story started many thousands of years ago,
但只历时了七天
but it was all over in just seven days.
在那个远古时代
All that long, long time ago,
我们现在熟悉的
none of the things we can see now,
太阳  月亮  星星  地球
the sun, the moon, the stars, the earth,
动物和植物  全部都不存在
the animals and plants not a single one existed.
只有上帝存在
Only God existed,
他是唯一的创造者
and so only He could have created them.
他创造了一切
And He did.
小 岛 惊 魂
"泽西岛  海峡群岛"  "1945年"
辛普森  真是大好人
Simpson. What a character he was.
现在不知怎么样了?
I wonder whatever became of him?
大概和其他人一样死了
Oh, I imagine he's dead like all the rest.
当时真是好时光
Ah, those were the days.
特德先生  注意你的头发
Mr. Tuttle, your hair.
什么事?
Yes?
早安  太太  我们是...
Good morning, ma'am. We've come about the...
哦  当然
Oh, yes, of course.
进来
Come in.
想不到这么快就到了
I wasn't expecting you so soon.
你们是?
You are?
我是贝莎米尔丝  太太
I'm Bertha Mills, ma'am.
这位是艾德蒙・特德
And this is Edmund Tuttle.
幸会  太太
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
你一定是花匠了
You must be the gardener.
没错  是花匠
That's right. The gardener.
这位姑娘叫丽蒂亚
And this young lady is called Lydia.
你有帮佣的工作经验吗?
Have you had much experience in service?
别被她的娃娃脸骗了  太太
Oh, don't let that angel face fool you, ma'am.
其实她年纪不轻
She's older than she looks.
会烫衣服吗?
Can you iron?
怎么了?  哑巴了?
What's the matter? Has the cat got your tongue?
她不会说话  太太
She can't talk, ma'am.
这个可怜的小姑娘是个哑巴
The poor little mite's a mute.
噢
Oh.
但手脚很灵活
Oh, but she's a good little worker.
这点我可以保证
I can promise you that.
好吧
All right.
从前那个姑娘太笨拙了
All right. The other girl I had spoke too much, anyway.
跟我来
Follow me.
米尔丝太太  你和姑娘的房间
Mrs. Mills, you and the girl
在顶楼
will sleep in the attic room at the top of the stairs.
-而你  -特德 太太
-And you, Mr.  -Tuttle, ma'am.
你可以睡在后面的库房
You could sleep in the shed around the back.
佣人们一周前失踪后
As you can see, the housework has been rather neglected
从那时起就没人打扫过
since the servants disappeared almost a week ago.
他们都不辞而别?
You mean they just vanished?
都蒸发了
Into thin air.
一声不响
No notice, nothing.
甚至连工资都没拿
They didn't even collect their wages. They...
都消失了
They just left us.
真奇怪!
What a strange thing to do.
你们不久就会发现
You'll soon find out there are times
这间屋子不是十全十美
when this house is not exactly an ideal home.
所以我在广告声明
Hence my advertisement in the newspaper
要老实  勤劳的人
requesting honest, hardworking people.
谁也不及我们老实  勤劳
There's nobody more honest or hardworking than us.
对吧  特德先生
Isn't that right, Mr. Tuttle?
我们是老实人
Oh, aye, we're very honest.
而且很勤劳
And, um, very hardworking.
这是厨房
The kitchen.
我八点用早餐
I have breakfast at 8:00
孩子们九点
the children at 9:00.
午餐一点  晚餐七点半
Lunch will be served at 1:00 and dinner at 7:30.
男主人呢  太太?
And the master, ma'am?
男主人一年半前
The master went off to war
去战场了
a year and a half ago.
停战后杳无音信
I've had no news since the war ended.
谁负责煮食?
Which of you does the cooking?
真遗憾  太太
I'm so sorry, ma'am
谁负责煮食?
Which of you does the cooking?
看到我做什么吗
You'll notice what I'm doing.
这间屋子关了门
In this house, no door must be opened
才可以开另一扇门
without the previous one being closed first.
一定要紧记
It is vital that you remember this.
实行起来不简单
It's not as easy as it may seem.
十五把锁匙开启五十扇门
There are 15 different keys for all of the 50 doors
要看你们在屋子的哪个地方
depending on which area of the house you're in at the time.
米尔丝太太  明天开始
Mrs. Mills, from tomorrow onwards
我会交一套钥匙给你负责
I will be leaving a set of keys in your charge.
好的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
音乐室
The music room.
我们搬来已有的那架老钢琴
That old piano was already here when we moved in.
不要让孩子们乱弹
Please do not let the children thump away on it.
我听了会头痛
It sets off my migraine.
安静
Silence is something that we prize
比什么都重要
very highly in this house.
屋子里没有电话  收音机
That is why you will not find a telephone, a radio
也没有任何弄出响声的东西
or anything else that makes a racket.
我们也没有电
Oh, we don't have electricity, either.
战争时  德国人不断切电
During the war, the Germans kept cutting it off
所以已经习惯了  我们继续生活在不用电的日子里
so we learned to live without it. Let's continue.
太太  其实没必要看整间屋子
Ma'am, there's no need to show us the whole house.
有!
Yes!
有必要
Yes, there is.
屋内经常漆黑一片不见五指
Most of the time, you can hardly see your way.
很难看清
It's often difficuIt to make out
有桌子椅子门餐柜
if there is a table, a chair, a door, a sideboard
或是孩子们在玩捉迷藏游戏
or one of my children playing hide and seek.
这话怎么说?
What do you mean, ma'am?
是时候见见我的孩子了
Perhaps I should introduce you to the children.
特德先生  请你现在去花园
Mr. Tuttle, you can see to the garden now.
工具在库房里
You'll find tooIs in the shed.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
你们两个拉上窗帘
You two can start closing the curtains.
全部窗帘
All of them.
来吧
Come.
我去叫醒他们  你们稍候
I'll wake them. You wait here.
千万别拉开窗帘
Whatever you do, don't open the curtains.
醒醒  醒醒
Wakey, wakey.
快醒醒
Now, come on.
合起眼  合起手
Eyes closed, hands together.
祈福日伊始
Let it be, at light of day
祷告主耶稣
Jesus, to whom now I pray.
祈福玛丽亚
Blessed be the Virgin pure
洁净如朝露
whom I greet with faith too short.
耶稣与玛丽  无瑕圣玫瑰
Jesus, Mary, spotless rose.
愿主保佑我  直至夕阳红
Keep us till this day doth close.
他们还未完全醒
They're still half asleep.
多可爱的孩子
What sweet little children.
应该说些什么呀?
Well what do you say?
你好吗?
How do you do?
你们好吗? 孩子们
How do you do, children?
我是米尔丝太太
My name is Mrs. Mills
不过也可以叫我贝莎
but you can call me Bertha if you like.
你们叫什么?
What are your names?
-安  -尼古拉斯
-Anne.  -Nicholas.
安和尼古拉斯  真是好听的名字
Anne and Nicholas. What pretty names.
你是新保姆?
Are you going to be our new nanny?
是的亲爱的  我是你们的新保姆
Yes, my dears. I'm your new nanny.
该吃早餐了
It's time for their breakfast.
丽蒂亚  去关上厨房的窗
Lydia, go to the kitchen and close every shutter.
医生找不到根治方法
The doctors were never able to find a cure.
治什么?
For what?
他们的病情
Their condition.
孩子们对光非常敏感
The children have a very serious allergy to light.
他们绝不能暴露在
They are photosensitive and must never be exposed
比现在强烈的光线之下
to any light much stronger than this.
否则他们即刻
Otherwise, in a matter of minutes
就会出现疱疹  呼吸困难
they will break out in sores and blisters
然后会开始窒息
and begin to suffocate.
严重的话会致命
It would eventually be fatal.
我的天
Good heavens.
我不喜欢这种土司
I don't like this toast.
哦?  为什么?
Oh? Why not?
味道怪怪的
It tastes funny.
从前的较好吃
I liked it better before.
因为从前是别人做的
That's because before, somebody else made it.
他们几时回来?
When are they coming back?
他们不会回来了  孩子们
They're not coming back, child.
和爸爸一样
Just like Daddy.
爸爸会回来的
Daddy is coming back, though.
米尔丝太太  爸爸去法国打仗
Mrs. Mills, our father's fighting in a war in France.
是世界大战
It's the World War.
我知道  但他在法国
I know, but he's in France.
说够了  别唧唧喳喳
That's enough, chatterboxes.
快吃早餐
Finish up your breakfasts.
你也会走吗?
Are you going to leave us, too?
当然不会
Of course not!
我为什么要走?
Why should I leave you?
他们也说不会
The others said they wouldn't
但还是走了  出事了
but they did, and then it happened.
别乱说!
Be quiet!
什么意思?
What do you mean, Anne?
出什么事了?
What happened?
妈妈变疯了
Mummy went mad.
-没事  -有事
-Nothing happened.  -Yes, it did.
-不  没事!  -有事的!
-No, it didn't!  -Yes, it did!
不要吵
Be quiet.
怎么回事?  我要你们
What's going on? I want those plates empty
一分钟内吃完  听到吗?
in less than a minute. Is that clear?
米尔丝太太  能出来一会吗?
Mrs. Mills, would you come outside a moment?
我有话和你说
I'd like a word with you.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
邮差每逢星期三来收信
The postman usually comes every Wednesday.
但我刚看了邮箱
But I just checked the letterbox
这星期他没来过
and this week he hasn't.
我不太明白太太的意思
I'm afraid I don't follow, ma'am.
这封信件应该
This letter should have been collected
在五天前送到报馆
and delivered to the newspaper five days ago.
就是聘佣广告
It's an advertisement for servants.
它没有刊登
Since it was never published
你们怎么会上门的?
would you explain what you're doing here?
噢  明白了
Oh, I understand.
太太  那就是你开门时
Ma'am, that's what I was going to say to you
我想解释的
when you opened the door to us.
事实上我们只是路过
The truth is that we just come by
碰碰运气
on the off chance.
这样的豪宅
A big house like this
通常需要我们这种老手
is always in need of someone who knows the ropes.
你们曾在类似的大屋工作过?
You've served in a house like this one before?
这真是巧得很  太太
This may come as a surprise to you, ma'am, but
我们其实就在这里干过活
we, in fact, used to work here.
这里?
Here?
是几年前的事了
Oh, now, it was a few years ago.
实不相瞒  太太
If you don't mind my saying so, ma'am
那是我一生最快乐的时光
they were the best years of my life.
我们路过是因为这间屋子
That's why we come by, because this house
对我们有特殊意义
means a lot to us.
或许我该出示推荐信  太太
Perhaps I'd best show you our references, ma'am.
不  不
No, no, no.
别担心  没必要
Don't bother. There's no need.
那你们很熟悉这屋子了?
So you say you know the house well?
了如指掌
Like the back of my hand.
除非墙生出了脚
That is assuming the walls haven't sprouted legs
移了位置
and moved in the meantime.
在这里移位的只有光
The only thing that moves here is the light.
但它改变了一切
But it changes everything.
令人感到困惑
It's rather difficult, to say the least.
可以说是难以忍受
One might almost say unbearable.
只有头脑冷静才能坚持下去
The only way of enduring it is by keeping a cool head.
对  太太
Oh, yes, ma'am.
我不喜欢无中生有
I don't like fantasies.
胡思乱想  明白吗?
Strange ideas. Do you know what I mean?
是的  太太
I think so, ma'am.
孩子们有时会胡言乱语
My children sometimes have strange ideas.
你别信以为真
But you mustn't pay any attention to them.
孩子毕竟是孩子
Children will be children.
当然  太太
Yes, of course, ma'am.
好吧  你们留下吧
All right. You can stay.
非常感谢  太太
Thank you very much, ma'am.
的确有事
It did happen.
罗马统治者后来试图
The Roman governor tried to make them
逼他们改变想法...
change their minds afterwards...
逼他们改变想法  句号
To make them change their minds. Full stop.
-后来  -嗯
-Afterwards  -Mm- hmm.
他下令对他们用刑
He ordered them to be beaten.
但祖斯特和巴斯达却不畏屈服
But Justus and Pastor, far from being afraid
乐意为基督而献身
rejoiced and showed themselves willing to die for Christ.
他见此情景
When he saw this,
统治者勃然大怒
the Roman governor was filled with rage
下令斩首示众
and ordered their heads to be cut off.
有什么好笑?
What do you find so amusing?
哇哦
Well.
哇哦  什么?
Well, what?
那些小孩真笨
Those children were really stupid.
为什么?
Why?
因为他们说只信耶稣
Because they said they only believed in Jesus
就为了这个被杀了
and then they got killed for it.
你会怎样? 背叛耶稣?
And what would you have done, deny Christ?
嗯  是的
Well, yes
我会暗地里信
Inside I would have believed in him
但不会说出来
but I wouldn't have told the Romans that.
你也那样认为?  尼古拉斯
Is that what you think, too, Nicholas?
明白了
I see.
你们宁愿撒谎  背弃耶稣
So you would have lied to the point of denying Christ.
暂时是可以保住脑袋
You'd have saved your heads from the Romans,
没错
that's true.
但之后怎样?
But what would have happened afterwards?
几时?
When?
死了之后
In the next life.
死后会去一个地方
The one waiting for us after we die.
你会到哪里去?
Where would you have gone?
去哪里?  尼古拉斯
Where, Nicholas?
去小孩的边狱
To the children's limbo.
什么是边狱?  安
What is the children's limbo, Anne?
四狱之一
One of the four Hells.
何谓四狱?
Which are?
我  我回答
Me, me, me! Me!
让他答  是什么?
No, Let him answer, Which are?
不赦之徒入地狱
There's the Hell where the damned go,
还有炼狱
then there's Purgatory.
是
Yes.
亚伯拉罕之胸狱
And the bosom of Abraham where the just go
小孩入边狱
and limbo where children go.
在地底中心
At the center of the earth.
非常非常热
Where it's very, very hot.
说谎的小孩去那里
That's where children go who tell lies
而且不是几天
but they don't just go there for a few days.
噢  不
Oh, no.
是永世不得超生
No, they're damned. Forever.
仔细想想
Think about it.
想想万劫不复
Try to imagine the end of eternity.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛想一下
Close your eyes and try to imagine it.
永世
Forever.
永世万劫不复
Pain forever.
我觉得头晕
I'm getting dizzy.
现在明白
Now do you understand
为何祖斯特和巴斯达不说谎?
why Justus and Pastor told the truth?
好了
All right.
翻到第六课
Open your readers at lesson six.
可以去玩吗?
Can't we play?
当然不可以
You most certainly cannot.
先熟读课文
First you're going to read the lesson
然后背诵全文
then you're going to learn it by heart.
全部?
All of it?
再讨价还价
Any more protests
今天就别想玩了
and there'll be no playing at all today.
对了  你们应该分开做功课
In fact, I think you can study in separate rooms.
不不不!
No, no, no!
就这样
Yes, yes, yes!
我们分开会害怕的
But we get scared if we're separated!
害怕?  你们早习惯这屋子了
Scared? As if you weren't used to this house by now.
看见鬼怎么办?
What if we see a ghost?
姐姐又讲鬼故事了?
Has your sister been telling you one of her stories?
我什么也没有讲
I haven't told him anything!
看见鬼就说你好
If you see a ghost you say "Hello"
然后继续念书
and continue on studying.
-安  跟我去音乐室  -为什么是我?
-Come to the music room.  -Why me?
因为我要你去  快点
Because I say so! Now come on.
拿好书本
Take your book.
尼古拉斯  我要你一小时内
Nicholas, I want to see that lesson learned
背熟全文
in less than an hour.
-妈咪  -什么?
-Mummy  -What?
吻我一下
Give me a kiss.
吻我一下 吻我一下
"Give me a kiss. Give me a kiss."
安  出去等我
Anne, wait for me outside.
你知道我不行
You know I can't.
来这边
Over there.
米尔斯太太  拉上窗帘
Mrs. Mills, close all the curtains.
我女儿要过客厅
My daughter is going to cross the living room.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
好了  安
All right, Anne.
宝贝
Darling.
妈妈不能整天陪你
Mummy can't be with you all the time, hmm?
你必须学会独立学习
You must learn to be on your own.
你的念珠呢?
Where's your rosary?
感到害怕时
Whenever you feel afraid,
就用力握紧它
I want you to squeeze it with all your might
念一次经文  就不会害怕了
say an Our Father, and your fear will go away.
-没用的  -当然有用
-It won't.  -Yes, it will. Honestly.
你要知道  念经的时候
Don't you see that when you do that
主与你同在
the Lord is with you?
不必感到害怕
There's no reason to be afraid.
屋子和家人
The house and the family
全家人都住在同一间屋
We all live in a house with our family.
家人包括双亲
The family is usually made up of parents,
孩子和其祖父母
children, and their grandparents.
我们要乖乖听话
We must be obedient
服从尊重其他家人
and kind towards other members of our family
兄弟姐妹之间
and we must never argue or fight
不应争吵打斗
with our brothers and sisters.
你有孩子吗?
Do you have any children?
没有
No.
只有特德先生和丽蒂亚
Mr. Tuttle and the girl Lydia are all I've got and
我也是他们的仅有
I'm all they've got.
她天生就是这样?
Was she born like that?
我不明白  太太
Beg your pardon, ma'am?
那个姑娘  她天生是哑巴?
The girl. Was she born a mute?
不
No.
这里我打扫干净了
I think I've finished here, ma'am.
如果没有什么事  我想出去
If you'll excuse me, I think I'll go
看看特德先生要不要帮忙
and see if Mr. Tuttle needs a hand.
尼古拉斯!
Nicholas!
尼古拉斯  我来了!
Nicholas, I'm coming!
噢!
Oh!
-尼古拉斯?  -什么事?
-Nicholas?  -What's the matter?
你哭什么?
Why were you crying?
我没哭  我在读书
I wasn't crying. I was reading.
我刚刚听到  安!
But I just heard you, Anne!
安!
Anne!
安?
Anne?
我还没背熟  妈妈
I haven't learned it yet, Mummy.
-你没事吧?  -是的
-Are you all right?  -Yes.
-你哭什么?  -我没哭
-Why were you crying?  -I wasn't.
我刚才明明听到
I just heard you a moment ago.
不必感到难为情  宝贝
There's no need to feel ashamed, darling.
我没哭
I don't.
要是我哭了  会告诉你的
If I'd been crying, I'd tell you.
那我是无中生有了?
Oh, really. So I imagined it, did I?
不  是那男孩在哭
No. It was that boy.
哪个男孩?
What boy?
维克多
Victor.
谁是维克多?
Who's Victor?
刚才在这里的男孩
The boy that was here a moment ago.
我叫他安静让我读书
I told him to let me study
但他不停地哭
but he wouldn't stop crying.
他很蛮不讲理
I think he's a spoiled brat.
要我们离开这屋子
He said we'd have to leave the house.
是吗?  那他为什么哭?
Oh, did he, now? And why was he crying?
因为他不喜欢这屋子
Because he doesn't like this house
但必须住着  他爸爸是钢琴家
but he has to live here. His father's a pianist.
-他爸爸是钢琴家?  -是的
-His father's a pianist?  -Yes.
我警告他不许碰钢琴
I already told him he's not allowed to touch the piano.
不能碰  对吗  妈妈?
He isn't, is he, Mummy?
你和他爸爸也说了?
So, you've spoken to his father as well?
没  只和维克多说了
No, only with Victor.
他爸爸和其他人都在厅里
His father's with the others in the hall.
我从厅里进来  那里没有人
I've just come from the hall. There's no one there.
大概是上楼去视察屋子了
They must've gone upstairs. They're viewing the house.
行了  安  够了
That'll do, Anne! That's enough!
你为什么要哭?
Now why were you crying?
是维克多在哭
It was Victor!
-他在哪里?  -他从那边出去了
-So where is he now?  -He went out through there!
那告诉我一个男孩
Would you mind telling me how a boy
门锁住了是怎么进出的?
can get in and out of this room if it's locked?
我说得很清楚了
I thought I made myseIf quite clear.
关门之后
No door is to be opened
才能开另一扇门
without the previous one being closed first.
难道不明白?
Is that so hard to understand?
这屋子就像船
This house is like a ship.
光线就像水必须排除在外
The light must be contained as if it were water
只能依靠开门  关门
by opening and closing the doors.
我的孩子有生命危险!
My children's lives are at stake!
太太
But, ma'am
别狡辩!  闭嘴!
Do not argue with me! Be quiet!
最后一个进房的是谁?
Which was the last of you to enter that room?
丽蒂亚?
Lydia?
她没有锁匙  我告诉过你
She hasn't got a key. I already told you that.
那就是你了
That leaves you, then.
我一直在厅里
But I was in the hall the whole time.
然后去了花园
And then I went out into the garden.
你亲眼看见的
You saw me with your own eyes.
你意思是指我了!
I hope you are not suggesting that it was me!
你以为我会粗心大意到
Do you think that I would overlook such a thing
害死自己的女儿?
and endanger the life of my own daughter?
不要在餐桌上看书
You're not supposed to read at the table.
那又怎样?
Oh, really?
谁会告诉妈妈?  你?
Who's going to tell Mummy? You?
或是你?
Or perhaps you?
你真的见到男孩?
Did you really see a boy?
是  他叫维克多
Yes. He's called Victor.
他是鬼吗?
Is he a ghost?
笨蛋  鬼不是那样的
Don't be stupid. Ghosts aren't like that.
那他们怎样的?
What are they like?
告诉你一千次了
I've told you a thousand times.
他们披白布戴锁链
They go about in white sheets and carry chains.
-你怎么知道?  -因为我见过
-How do you know?  -Because I've seen them.
他们晚上行动
They come out at night.
胡说  在哪里?
Fibber. Where?
-你笨蛋  -没你笨
-You're stupid.  -Not half as much as you.
我才不信你见到了那个男孩
I don't believe you saw that boy.
信不信由你
Believe what you like.
很快你就会要我们陪你玩
You'll soon be begging us to play with you.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas!
干嘛?
What?
看
Look.
你为何拉开窗帘?
Why have you opened the curtains?
-不是我  -那是谁?
-It wasn't me.  -Who was it, then?
是维克多
It was Victor.
他搞了一晚
He's been doing it all night.
说谎  我要告诉妈妈
You're lying. I'm going to tell Mummy.
-我说谎?  -是
-So I'm a liar, am I?  -Yes.
维克多  快从窗帘后出来
Victor, come out from behind that curtain
让我笨弟弟看看
so my stupid brother can see you.
不要吓我
Leave me alone.
你不想见他?
So you don't want to see him now, eh?
你是胆小鬼
You're a cowardy custard.
胆小  胆小  胆小鬼
Cowardy cowardy custard.
我只好亲自动手了
I'll just have to do it myself, then.
够了  维克多
That's enough, Victor
尼古拉斯  尼古拉斯
Nicholas. Nicholas.
叫他别弄窗帘
Tell him to leave the curtains alone.
他不听我的话
He won't listen to me.
住手  你们两个离开我的床
Stop it, Get off my bed, both of you.
床是我们的
This is our bed.
不  是我的
No, it's mine
安  不要扮怪声
Anne, please stop putting on that voice.
闭嘴  胆小鬼
You be quiet, cowardy custard.
听着  还不停手  我就叫妈妈
Listen, if you don't stop, I'll call my mother
赶你出去
and she'll kick you out.
你见识过她的厉害
You don't know my mother.
你未见识过我的父母
And you don't know my parents.
安  我要告诉妈妈你吓我
Anne, I'm going to tell Mummy about you.
真笨  不是我
Don't be stupid. Can't you see it's not me?
维克多  摸他的脸让他感觉一下
Victor, touch his cheek so he knows you're real.
妈咪!  救命!
Mummy! Help!
救命!  救命!  妈咪
Help! Help, Mummy!
什么事?  什么事?
What is it? What is it?
出什么事?
What is it?
她吓我  我叫她别说了
She was fighting with me, and I told her to be quiet.
我忍无可忍  听到吗!
I'm fed up. Do you hear me?
你太过份了!
I am fed up with you!
不是我干的
I didn't do anything!
因此上帝将他
Therefore the Lord God sent him forth
从伊甸园
from the Garden of Eden
放逐到农田耕地
to till the ground from whence he was taken.
他赶走众人
So he drove out the man
在伊甸园东首
and placed to the east of the Garden of Eden
竖立起烈火剑
cherubims and a flaming sword
旋回转动  确保了
which turned every way to keep the way
生命之树世代相传
of the Tree of Life,
行了  我念完了
There, I finished.
很好
Very good.
现在向圣母认错
Now you can ask the Virgin for forgiveness.
什么?  我们没这样说过
What? That's not what we agreed!
我们不必说什么
We didn't agree anything, young lady.
今天你受罚  一切我说了算
Today you're being punished, and you'll do as I say.
您不能逼我向圣母认错
You can't make me ask the Virgin for forgiveness.
大胆
How dare you!
妈妈  我不会为没做过的事认错
Mummy, I won't ask forgiveness for something I didn't do!
你告诉弟弟房间里有人
You told your brother someone else was in the room!
-的确有!  -你说谎!
-There was!  -You're lying!
我没有!
I am not!
安
Anne,
记得祖斯特和巴斯达的故事吗?
do you remember the story about Justus and Pastor?
说谎的小孩入边狱
Children who don't tell the truth end up in limbo.
那是你说的  我看过书
That's what you say, but I read the other day
边狱是未受洗礼的小孩去的
that limbo's only for children who haven't been baptized.
我已受过洗礼
And I have!
亚伯拉罕将炭木
And Abraham took the wood
置予儿子以撒的身上
of the burnt offering and laid it upon lsaac his son.
他手持火把与利刃
And he took the fire in his hand and a knife
两人一起离去
and they went, both of them together.
以撒对亚伯拉罕说
And lsaac spake unto Abraham his father
"我父啊"
and said, 'My father'
他回道:"我在  孩子"
and he said, "Here I am, my son,"
去看过尼古拉斯吗?
Did you look in on Nicholas?
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
他如小天使般睡着了
The little angel is fast asleep.
安呢?
What about Anne?
还在楼梯上?
Is she still on the stairs?
是的  太太
Oh, yes, ma'am.
我倒是想看着她
I'd prefer to have her where I can see her
但那里光线太暗无法刺绣
but I can't embroider in such poor light.
还要惩罚多久?
How long is this punishment going to go on?
已经有三天了
It's been three days now.
这要取决于她了
It's up to her.
她必须懂得收敛嚣气
She's got to learn to swallow her pride
低头认错
and ask for forgiveness.
而且也是时候读读圣经了
Anyway, it's time she started to read the Bible.
神父知道了会很高兴的
The priest will be very pleased to hear that, ma'am.
他能上门一次就好了
If he ever deigns to pay us another visit.
他明知孩子们不能出门
He knows perfectly well that the children can't go out.
昨天他说了
He told me yesterday
他会尽快登门造访
he'd be by as soon as possible.
我渐渐觉得完全与世隔绝
I'm beginning to feel totally cut off from the world.
尤其是这片迷雾
This fog doesn't exactly help.
如此之久都未散去
It's never lasted this long before.
没错  太太
Oh, that's true, ma'am.
连海鸥都销声匿迹了
Even the seagulls have gone quiet.
安!
Anne!
安  我听不到你读书
Anne, I can't hear you.
米尔丝太太  坦白地说
Incidentally, Mrs. Mills,
我真受不了
I've had to put up with the noise
丽蒂亚在楼上大声走动
of Lydia running around above my head.
她走来走去
She's been hurtling backwards and forwards
吵得就像有三个人
as if there were three of her.
请你告诉她
Would you kindly tell her it's not necessary
清洁不必如此
to kick up quite such a rumpus
兴师动众
just to do a little cleaning?
我不想头痛又再发作
I couldn't bear to get another migraine attack.
我会告诉她  太太
I'll tell her, ma'am.
谢谢
Thank you.
她太过份了
Now she's really gone too far.
丽蒂亚!  丽蒂亚!
Lydia! Lydia!
能看见上帝之巅
in the mount of the Lord it shall be seen.
然后上帝的天使...
And the angel of the Lord...
楼上怎么了?
What's going on up there?
没事  妈妈  我在念书
Nothing, Mummy. I'm just reading.
-你听到吗?  -听到什么?
-Did you hear it as well?  -Hear what?
然后上帝的天使
And the angel of the Lord
再次呼唤亚伯拉罕入天堂
called unto Abraham out of Heaven
并说道,
the second time and said,
以我名义已发誓忠奉上帝...
By myself, I have sworn, saith the Lord...
是什么?
What was that?
不知道
I don't know.
安  告诉我谁在弄响声
Anne, tell me who's making that noise.
我不能告诉你  妈妈
I can't tell you, Mummy.
告诉我
You tell me.
我说过有人在房间里
I told you there was someone in the room
你就惩罚我
and you punished me.
要我怎么说
Now I don't know what to say.
安  告诉我真相
Anne, I want the truth.
告诉我楼上有没有人
Tell me if there is someone upstairs.
在杂物房间里
There. In that junk room.
妈咪  你让光照进来了
Mummy, you're letting the light in.
-是个女的  -是什么?
-She's a woman,  -She's what?
他们去哪里了?
Where did they go?
刚经过  你没看见吗?
They just came past here. Didn't you see them?
往哪里去了?
Which way did they go?
那里  那里  还有下面
Over there, over there, and down there as well.
到处都有  他们说屋子是他们的
They're everywhere. They say this house is theirs.
还说要把窗帘都拆下
And they're going to take the curtains down as well.
太太  请镇静
Ma'am, stay calm, please.
我无法镇静
I will not stay calm!
沦陷的五年来
For five whole years during the occupation
我阻止了纳粹踏入这间屋子
I managed to avoid a single Nazi stepping foot in this house
现在居然有人在这里擅自出入
and now there is someone here, opening and closing the doors.
太太  这已是老房子
Ma'am, this is a very old house.
地板水管时常会有响声
The floorboards squeak and the plumbing clanks.
分明是说话声
There were voices. I'm telling you.
-妈妈  你看  -有男孩和两个女人在说话
-Mummy, look!  -A boy and two women, talking together.
妈妈  你看
Mummy, look!
我昨天画的
I did it yesterday.
这是父亲  母亲
This is the father, this is the mother,
维克多  还有老妇人
this is Victor, and this is the old woman.
这些数字是什么意思?
What do these numbers stand for?
是我看见他们的次数
That's the number of times I've seen them.
老妇人最常见
I've seen the old woman the most.
噢  我的天
Oh, God in Heaven.
米尔丝太太  去叫特德先生  告诉他
Mrs. Mills, go and call Mr. Tuttle. Tell him
我们要立刻搜屋
we have to search the whole house immediately
天黑前必须搜清楚
before it gets dark.
-是的  太太  这就去  -妈咪!
-Yes, ma'am. There, now.  -Mummy!
宝贝  别怕
Yes, darling. It's all right.
妈妈会保护你们
Nothing will happen to you while Mummy's here.
妈妈  我真的好害怕
Look, Mummy, She really scares me.
看起来她没在看你
It's as if she's not looking at you,
其实她盯着你
but she can see you.
整天都在说  "跟我来"
And she's always around saying "Come with me".
安  别对我说谎
No, Anne, don't lie to me.
我没说谎  她还问这问那
Honestly, Mummy, and she asks me things.
维克多说她是巫婆
Victor told me she's a witch.
问你什么?
What does she ask you?
什么都问
Things.
她呼吸散发臭味
Her breath smells.
必须拉开所有窗帘
We have to open all the curtains.
搜遍每一个昏暗角落
I don't want any dark corners where someone could hide.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
你们两个搜右面
You both search the right side
我搜左面
and I'll take the left.
然后上楼搜
Then we'll search upstairs.
也许他们是鬼
Perhaps they're ghosts
从前就住在这屋子
who lived in this house before.
别犯傻  告诉过你
Don't be stupid. I've already told you.
鬼披着白布
Ghosts go about in white sheets
戴着锁链  并且发出呜呜的声音
and carry chains and go "Ooo".
安
Now, Anne.
你为什么胡编故事?
Why do you make up such stories?
不是编的  书上写的
I don't. I read them in books.
你不可全信
Well, you shouldn't believe everything
书上写的东西
that you read in books.
妈妈也这么说
That's what our mother says.
她说鬼故事都是垃圾
She says all this stuff about ghosts is rubbish
她要我们
and then she expects us
相信圣经里写的东西
to believe everything written in the Bible.
你信不信?
And don't you believe it?
不可不信
I believe some things.
但不可全信  比如不信
But, for example, I don't believe
上帝七天创造了世界
that God made the world in seven days.
也不信诺亚方舟
And I don't believe that Noah
能装载全部的动物
got all those animals into one boat
不信圣灵是鸽子
or the Holy Spirit is a dove.
对  我也不信
No, I don't believe that, either.
鸽子根本不神圣
Doves are anything but holy.
它们在窗台拉屎
They poo on our windows.
和你妈妈说过这些吗?
Have you mentioned any of this to your mother?
哦
Oh.
太太
Ma'am.
什么事?
Yes?
到处都搜过了  太太
They've searched everywhere, ma'am.
没有人
There's no one.
知道了
I see.
米尔丝太太
Mrs. Mills.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am?
你对这个有何见解?
Do you have any idea what this might be?
是本相册  太太
This is a photograph album, ma'am.
看  他们都睡着了
No, but look. They're all asleep.
看
Look.
他们不是在睡觉  是死了
They're not asleep, ma'am. They're dead.
这是本遗照相册
This is a book of the dead.
在上个世纪
In the last century, I believe
人死后通常被拍成遗照
they used to take photographs of the dead
以期待他们的灵魂
in the hopes that their souls
能得以续存于世
would go on living through the portraits.
甚至有集体照
There are even group portraits.
还有小孩
And children!
噢  太可怕了
Oh, it's macabre!
怎么会如此迷信?
How could these people be so superstitious?
失去亲人的悲情
Grief over the death of a loved one
会令人做出不可思议的事
can lead people to do the strangest things.
扔掉它  别留在屋里
Get rid of it, I don't want it in the house.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am
米尔丝太太  这里很冷
Mrs. Mills, it's cold.
何不坐过来取暖?
Why don't you come and sit by the fire?
太谢谢了  太太
Thank you very much, ma'am.
说说你以前在这里干活的事
So tell me about when you worked here before.
也要照看小孩吗?
Did you have to look after children then?
不  我只负责管家
No, I was in charge of organizing the housework.
嗯  有很多佣人吗?
Hmm. Were there many servants?
大概有十五个
Oh, about fifteen.
不过最后
Though in the end
只剩下我们三个
there were just the three of us left.
为什么?
Why?
主人搬到伦敦去了
My employers moved to London.
他们渐渐就不常来了
They came here less and less,
没了以前那么热闹
it being so out of the way like.
屋子就这样被空置了
So gradually the house just became empty.
大家最终都离开这个岛
Everybody ends up leaving this damned island.
1940年夏  我家人也走了
My family left in the summer of 1940
就在沦陷之前
just before the invasion.
此后再也没有音讯
That was the last I've heard of them.
噢
Ohh.
我不责怪他们
I don't blame them.
其实我们也走了
Actually, we left, too.
但你知道
Although, you know,
有时即使是人走了
sometimes when you leave a place
心还是一直在
it's like it's there with you all the time.
我总觉得从未离开过这间屋
I always felt like I never left this house.
你为什么要走?
Why did you leave?
是因为肺结核肆虐
Oh, it was on account of the tuberculosis.
全区都被疏散了
The whole area was evacuated.
噢
Ohh.
丽蒂亚因此变成哑巴了?
Was that when Lydia went dumb?
我想是的
Yes, I think so
不过近来我的记性不太好
though my memory's a bit rusty these days, ma'am.
她发生什么事了?
What happened to her?
有一天她突然
It was suddenly one day,
不再说话了
she just stopped talking.
必定有原因
There must've been a reason.
不会莫名其妙变哑巴
People don't just stop talking.
一定是受到什么
These things are always the result
精神刺激之类的事
of some sort of trauma.
肯定发生了一些事
Something must've happened to her.
主人对你们好吗?
Did your employers treat you well?
他们对我们很好
Oh, they were always very kind to us.
视我们如同一家人
They treated us just like family.
太太  我该去休息了
You know, ma'am, I think I will go to bed.
否则明天不能早起
I'll never be able to get up in the morning.
去吧
Off you go.
我想一个人再坐会儿
I'm going to stay here a while longer.
好  太太
Yes, ma'am.
妈妈对你太严格了
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
原谅妈妈好吗?
Can you forgive me?
安
Anne.
妈咪
Mummy.
怎么了?
What?
爸爸几时回来?
When's Daddy coming home?
打完仗就回来
When the war's over.
他为什么去打仗?
Why did he go to war?
没有人欺负我们的
I mean, nobody's done anything bad to us.
爸爸去...
Daddy went...
是因为他很勇敢
Daddy went because he's very brave
因为他不愿意
and because he wasn't prepared
屈服听从德国人
to let the Germans tell him what he had to do.
为什么?
Why?
查尔斯
Charles,
你在哪里?
where are you?
米尔丝太太!
Mrs. Mills!
什么事?  太太
What's the matter, ma'am?
快给我音乐室的锁匙
The key to the music room, give it to me!
快点!
Quickly!
怎么了?
What's happening, ma'am?
快点!
Come on!
噢  天哪
Oh, my God.
噢!
Ohh!
我亲自查过房间
I checked that room myself.
里面没有人
It was empty.
吃点药片  太太
Take these tablets, ma'am.
-但...  -对你身体有益
-And yet...  -They'll do you good.
我感到那里确实有人
I felt as if there was someone else there.
不是人类
And it wasn't human.
屋里有东西
There is something in this house.
不祥之物
Something diabolic.
太太
Ma'am.
那是尚未...
Something which is not...
尚未得到安息的冤魂
not at rest.
我知道你不相信
I know you don't believe it.
你不信的  对吗?
You don't believe it, do you?
我不责怪你
I don't blame you.
以前我也不信
I used to not believe these things.
我相信  太太
I do believe it, ma'am.
我一直都相信这些事
I've always believed in those things.
虽然难以说清
They're not easy to explain,
但确实存在
but they do happen.
幽灵的故事
We've all heard stories of the beyond
我们时有所闻
now and then,
我想有时阴界
and I think sometimes the world of the dead
会和阳界交错在一起
gets mixed up with the world of the living.
这不可能
But it's impossible.
上帝绝不允许这种异事
The Lord would never allow such an aberration.
活人和死人
The living and the dead
只有在终世审判时才相会
will only meet at the end of eternity.
圣经是这么写的
It says so in the Bible.
太太
Ma'am,
不是所有事都有合理解释
there isn't always an answer for everything.
太太您要上哪里?
Where are you off to, ma'am?
我要去村庄拜访迈格拉神父
I'm going to the village to pay Father McGraw a visit.
他不愿来  我就上门
If he won't come here, then I shall go to him.
我要带他来这里
I shall bring him back.
太太您应该等天气变好
Ma'am, you should wait till the weather improves.
我等得太久了
I've waited long enough.
太太  神父告诉我...
Ma'am, the priest told me that...
我不管他告诉你什么
I don't care what he told you!
我要他亲自告诉我
I want him to tell me personally!
他今天一定得来
He must come today!
那你打算怎么说?
But what are you going to tell him?
我们搜遍了整间屋子
That we have searched every room inch by inch,
现在需要他的祈福
and now I need them to be blessed.
太太  请等等
Ma'am, please, wait.
现在太早了
Still, it's very early.
-特德先生  -早安  太太
-Mr. Tuttle.  -Morning, ma'am.
我要你在花园里找墓碑
I need you to search the garden for gravestones.
墓碑?
Gravestones?
对  我先生买屋时
Yes. When my husband bought this house
我们听说这里有个小墓地
we were told there was a little cemetery.
好像就在那里的树林里
I think it was over there, amongst the trees.
我没看见
I've not seen anything.
仔细查  可能被遮住了
Check carefully. It could be overgrown.
好的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
看看是否有一家人葬在这里
I need to know if there was a family buried here
是否有个叫维克多的男孩
and if they had a little boy Victor.
她认为屋子里闹鬼
Now she thinks the house is haunted.
让她出去安全吗?
Do you think it's safe to let her go?
放心
Oh, don't worry.
她在迷雾里走不远
The fog won't let her get very far.
说得对  迷雾
Oh, yes, the fog.
迷雾  没错
The fog, of course.
你认为几时
And when do you think
我们才该揭露真相?
we should bring all this out into the open?
快了  特德先生
All in good time, Mr. Tuttle.
快了
All in good time.
说到真相
Speaking of which.
查尔斯?
Charles?
葛蕾丝?
Grace?
你回来了  你回来了
You're here. You're here.
他们说已经没希望了
They said there was no hope.
他们叫我死心  说就当你死了
They said I should give you up for dead.
他们口无遮拦
They say a lot of things.
噢  谢谢
Oh, thank you.
感谢上帝
Thank you, God.
每晚我祈求上帝
Every night I prayed for this,
让你平安归来
begging God to bring you back.
让孩子重享天伦之乐
Bring the children their father back.
让他归来
Bring him.
你究竟去了哪里?
But where have you been all this time?
我一直在找回家的路
Out there looking for my home.
你变了很多
You're so different.
变了很多
So different.
有时我会流血
Sometimes I bleed.
太太
Ma'am.
米尔丝太太
Mrs. Mills,
这位是我先生
this is my husband.
真是幸会  先生
I'm very pleased to meet you, sir.
他很虚弱
He's very weak.
这边
Here.
去准备热水澡和些干净衣服
I want you to prepare a hot bath and some clean clothes.
再弄点吃的
And something to eat.
这就去  太太
Right away, ma'am.
我的小宝贝都好吗?
How are my little ones?
爸爸!
Daddy!
你怎么去了那么久?
Why did you take so long?
你好  尼古拉斯
Hello, Nicholas.
我说了  是不是
I told you, you see.
我说了他会回来的
I told you he'd come back.
你们乖不乖?
Have you both been well-behaved?
我们很乖
We've been very good.
听不听妈妈的话?
Have you been good to your mother?
听
Very good.
我们天天都为圣礼而学习
We study every day for our First Communion.
爸爸  你杀了人吗?
Daddy, did you kill anyone?
噢  他来了
Oh! Here he comes!
亲爱的  午餐准备好了
Darling, we've prepared lunch for you.
你下来吃还是想...
Are you coming down or would you prefer...
爸爸几时下来?
When's Daddy coming down?
别吵  安  爸爸不舒服
Be patient, Anne, Daddy is not well.
他说见到很多死人
He said he'd seen a lot of dead men.
妈咪  战争中死去的人
Mummy, when people die in the war,
会去哪里?
where do they go?
问得真好
Oh, what a question.
-要看情况  -什么情况?
-It depends.  -On what?
看他们为正义还是邪恶而战
Whether they fought on the side of the goodies or the baddies.
你们的爸爸为英国而战
Your father, for example, fought for England
是正义的一方
on the side of the goodies.
怎么知道谁是正义谁是邪恶?
How do you know who the goodies and the baddies are?
问得太多了  快吃
That's enough questions. Eat your food.
你不用去打仗
You'll never go to war.
我们哪里也去不了
We'll never go anywhere.
不出去没什么关系
You're not missing out on anything.
在家里和爸爸妈妈一起最开心
You're much better off at home with your Mummy and Daddy
他们最疼爱你们
who love you very, very much.
还有不速之客
And the intruders.
这里没不速之客
There are no intruders here.
但你说过有的
But you said that there were.
不  我说没有
No, I said that there are no intruders here.
不要再为这事争执了
I don't want to hear another word on the subject.
-但你说...  -够了!
-But you said...  -That is enough!
我不能说话吗?
Can I say something?
-不能!  -为什么?
-No!  -Why not?
因为  你不能!
Because you can't!
安  不要那样呼吸
Anne, stop breathing like that.
听到吗  停止!
You heard me, Stop it!
停止呼吸
Stop breathing.
好  进你房间去
Right, you go to your room.
进房间  今天你没甜点吃
Go to your room. No dessert for you today.
不要哭  不要哭
Ohh, no crying now, no crying.
别哭了
Oh, stop that here.
看你哭起来变成丑八怪了
Look what an awful face you've got when you cry.
我不管
I don't care!
那里  还有那里
There, there.
听我说
You listen to me.
我也见过他们
I've seen them, too.
真的?
You have?
是
Yes.
何不告诉我妈妈
Why don't you tell my mother?
她就会信我
Then maybe she'll believe me.
有些事你妈妈听不进去
There are things your mother doesn't want to hear.
她只相信书本上的东西
She only believes in what she was taught.
但是放心  迟早
But don't worry, sooner or later,
她会见到他们
she'll see them.
然后一切都会改变
Then everything will be different.
怎样改?
How?
到时你就知道了
Oh, you'll see.
会有出乎意料的事
There are going to be some big surprises.
会有大改变
There are going to be changes.
改变?
Changes?
现在她装得若无其事
Now she's behaving as if nothing had happened.
她女儿呢?
What about her daughter?
她不太固执
Oh, she's not so stubborn.
小孩比较容易哄骗
The children will be easier to convince.
问题是母亲比较棘手
No, it's the mother who's going to cause us problems.
她的丈夫起疑心吗?
Do you think her husband suspects anything?
不  他根本不知道身在何处
No. I don't think he even knows where he is.
啊  我的女儿真漂亮
Ohh, look what a pretty daughter I've got.
妈妈特地为你缝了面纱
Mummy made this veil especially for you.
我像个新娘
I look like a bride.
是  说得对
Yes. You do.
袖子要改短些
I need to shorten the sleeves a little.
脱下来吧
You can take it off now.
不
No.
这是受圣礼穿的  要洁白无瑕
This dress has to be spotless for your First Communion.
我不会弄脏的
I promise I won't dirty it.
再让我穿一会儿
Just let me wear it for a little longer. Just a little.
噢  就一会?
Oh, just a little?
好吧  我马上回来
All right. I'll be back shortly.
别坐在地上或蹭到墙上
No sitting on the floor or leaning against the walls.
不会的
No.
先生  能赏面跳只舞吗?
Monsieur, would you like to dance?
荣幸之至
I'd love to.
查尔斯  不要再这样
Charles, you can't go on like this.
你得吃点东西
You must eat something.
天空
In the sky,
不知晴或雨
I don't know if it's cloudy or bright.
眼中只得
But I only have eyes
爱人你一个
for you, dear.
月亮不知圆或...
The moon may be high...
安  现在脱下礼服
Anne, you need to take the dress off now.
安  听见了吗?
Anne, are you listening to me?
安?
Anne?
我叫你不要坐在地上
What did I tell you about sitting on the floor?
地上很干净
But it's clean.
干净又怎样
It makes no difference.
你怎么就这么不听话...
Why can't you ever do as you're told...
怎么了?
What's the matter?
我女儿呢?
Where is my daughter?
你把我女儿怎么了?
What have you done with my daughter?
你疯了?  我就是你女儿
Are you mad? I am your daughter.
不  你不是我女儿
No! You're not my daughter!
不!  不!
No! No!
你不是我女儿!  不!
You're not my daughter! No!
不!  啊!
No! Aah!
太太  我听到尖叫声
Ma'am, I heard shouts.
她要杀我!
She wants to kill me!
她不杀死我们不罢休!
She won't stop until she kills us!
她不会罢休!
She won't stop!
好了  乖乖  跟我来
Hush, child. Come with me.
你恶毒!  恶毒!  恶毒!
You're wicked! You're wicked! Wicked!
恶毒!
Wicked!
她怎样了?
How is she?
她无法平静
There's no calming her,
我交给她爸爸安抚
so I've left her with her father.
她坚持要和他说话
She insisted on speaking with him.
发生什么事?  为什么打她?
What happened? Why did you fight?
不是她
It wasn't her.
是个有怪眼的老妇人
It was the old woman with the strange eyes.
模仿我女儿的声音
She was imitating my daughter's voice.
我向上帝发誓不是我女儿
I'd swear to God that it wasn't my daughter.
噢  主啊  帮帮我
Oh, God. God help me.
老天  我这是怎么了?
God help me. What's the matter with me?
不知道我究竟怎么了
I don't know what's the matter with me.
你要多休息
You must get more rest.
别再为屋子烦劳操心了
You can't take on the whole responsibility of this house.
让我们来
Leave it to us.
我们知道该做什么
We know what has to be done.
什么意思?
What do you mean by that?
"知道做什么"是什么意思?
What do you mean you know what has to be done?
没什么  我只不过建议...
Nothing, ma'am. I was just suggesting...
没什么好建议的
There's nothing to suggest.
你们懂什么?
Who do you think you are?
你们不知该做什么
You have no idea what has to be done.
或许知道?
Or do you?
这是什么?
What are these?
头痛药片  太太
The tablets for your migraine, ma'am.
你一直服用的
The ones you always take.
拜托了  我想静一静
Please, I need to be on my own.
是的  太太
Yes, ma'am.
来  孩子
Come, child.
安都告诉我了
Anne told me everything.
我希望能解释  但办不到
I wish I had an explanation, but I haven't.
起初我以为屋里有人
At first, I thought there was someone else in the house.
甚至想是鬼
Even thought there were ghosts.
我要说的不是鬼的事
I'm not talking about the ghosts.
是那天发生的事
I'm talking about what happened that day.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
告诉我那不是真的
Tell me it's not true.
告诉我发生了什么
Tell me what happened.
发生?
Happened?
我不知那天发生了什么
I don't know what came over me that day.
佣人半夜都走了
The servants had left during the night.
他们不敢当面和我说
Hadn't the courage to tell me to my face.
他们知道我不会离开这屋子
They knew that I couldn't leave the house.
他们知道的
They knew.
安
Anne.
安  怎么了?
Anne, what happened?
她打我
She hit me.
她疯了  像那天一样
She went mad like she did that day.
你还记得吗?
Do you remember?
不
No.
原谅我  查尔斯
You must forgive me, Charles.
求孩子们原谅你吧
Not me. The children.
他们知道我爱他们
They know that I love them.
不会伤害他们
They know I'd never hurt them.
我愿为他们而死
I'd die first.
你想做什么?
What are you going to do?
生我的气了?
Are you angry with me?
我回来只是想
I just came back to say good-bye
和妻儿道别
to my wife and children.
我得走了
Now I must go.
去哪里?
Go where?
去前线
To the front.
不  战争结束了
No. The war's over.
战争还没结束
The war is not over.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
不要去  听到吗?
You're not going, do you hear me?
你已经丢下我们一次了  不能再去
You left us once already. You can't go!
为什么?
Why?
为什么你要去打仗?
Why did you have to go to that stupid war
打毫无意义的仗?
that had nothing to do with us?
你就不能像其他人一样留下?
Why couldn't you have stayed here like the others?
他们投降了
The others surrendered.
我们都投降了!
We all surrendered!
全岛沦陷了!
The whole island was occupied!
还有什么办法?
What did you expect?
你去打仗有何意义?
What were you trying to prove by going to war?
这里才是你的家
Your place was here with us.
和家人在一起
With your family.
我爱你
I loved you.
我够知足了
That was enough for me.
守着这片黑暗
Living in this darkness.
守着这个监狱
In this prison.
但你不满足
But not for you,
你不满足于我
I wasn't enough for you.
所以要离我而去
That's why you left.
打仗只是藉口
It wasn't just the war.
你想离开我  是不是?
You want to leave me, don't you?
安!
Anne!
尼古拉斯!
Nicholas!
怎么了?
What is it? What?
噢  天啊
Oh, my God!
这里  老天
Here! Oh, my God!
这边
Here!
窗帘呢?
Where are the curtains?
米尔丝太太
Mrs. Mills!
让我看看  让我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
噢  你没事的!
Oh, you're all right!
你没事的!
You're all right!
我要爸爸
I want my daddy!
爸爸走了
Daddy's gone.
你骗我!
It's not true!
没骗你
Yes, it is.
是真的
It is true.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, Mummy.
找回窗帘
Find the curtains.
是谁?
Who was it?
谁干的?
Who did this?
快说!
Tell me!
告诉我!
你知道这里发生了什么
You know what's happening here!
因为你也经历了!
You know because it happened to you, too!
告诉我
You'll tell me.
写下来
You write it down.
写下来  求你
Write it down! Please!
那种态度只会更坏事  太太
That attitude won't solve anything, ma'am.
何况她不会写字
Anyway, she can't write.
-在哪里?  -什么?
-Where are they?  -What?
窗帘!
The curtains!
孩子们赖以生存的窗帘
The curtains my children's lives depend on!
有人拆了窗帘!
Someone has taken the curtains!
我看到了  太太
I have noticed, ma'am.
不必这样大声叫唤
There's no need for you to raise your voice.
特德先生  我正想找你
Oh, Mr. Tuttle. I was just on the point of calling you.
你注意到有人拆了窗帘吗?
Did you know that someone has taken all the curtains?
窗帘?
The curtains?
噢  是啊
Oh, dear.
怎么会有人要拆窗帘?
Why should anyone want to take all the curtains?
我想是想让日光照进来
To let some daylight into this house, I imagine.
日光  对啊
Daylight. Of course.
有人想害死我的孩子
Someone wants to kill my children.
为什么日光会害死他们?
Why do you think that the daylight would kill them?
你疯了?
Are you mad?
我告诉过你
I told you.
我已经说过
I already told you!
孩子对光线敏感
The children are photosensitive!
见光会死的!
The light will kill them!
是  那时从前
Yes, but that was before.
现在情形或许有所不同
The condition could have cleared up by itself.
不让日光照进来
If you never expose them to daylight
你怎么知道他们敏感?
how do you Know they're not cured?
我嫂子本来有严重风湿病
My sister-in-law had terrible attacks of rheumatism
在腿部和背部
in her legs and back.
后来有一天
Then one fine day
突然就治愈了
they disappeared.
我要找回窗帘
I am going to find those curtains
你们替我挂上之后
and when you have finished helping me hang them
请你们立刻走人
you will leave this house!
男主人怎么说?  太太
And what about the master, ma'am?
他有什么意见?
What has he got to say about all of this?
把钥匙给我
Give me your keys.
快把钥匙给我!
I want your keys now!
我知道你们想干嘛
I know what you want.
你们想吓唬我们
You want to frighten us.
想把我和孩子都吓走
You want to get us out, me and my children.
由第一天起
You've wanted to take over this house
你们就想霸占这间屋子
ever since the first day you arrived.
现在把锁匙给我  一笔勾销
Now, you give me those keys. I will not ask again.
请你镇静点  太太
You should try and calm down, ma'am.
把锁匙给我!
Give me the keys.
快给我
Give them to me.
立刻滚出去
And now get out of here.
你怎么认为?  特德先生
You know something, Mr. Tuttle?
我已经是忍无可忍
I think I've reached the end of my tether.
你呢?
What about you?
完全同意
Oh, yes. Definitely.
是时候去揭开墓碑了
We'd better go and uncover the gravestones.
妈妈在做什么?
What's Mummy doing?
我告诉你了  她疯了
I've already told you. She's gone mad.
说谎
Liar.
-疯了!  疯了!  -说谎!  说谎!
-She's gone mad!  -Liar, liar!
九点
Nighttime.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我受够了
I've had enough.
我要去树林找爸爸
I'm going into the woods to look for Daddy.
你是想出走?
Are you going to run away?
如果我沿着水管向下爬
If I hang onto the pipe
就能到屋外院子里
I can climb down to the ground.
非常容易
It's very easy.
妈妈知道了  你就惨了
If Mummy finds out, you're in for it.
好  好
Yes, yes, yes.
安  等等
Anne, wait!
我也要去找爸爸
I want to come and look for Daddy, too.
说谎  你不敢一个人呆着
Liar. You just don't want to be left on your own.
胆小鬼  胆小鬼
Scaredy-pants, scaredy-pants!
住嘴!
Be quiet!
安  我们迷路了
Anne, I think we got lost.
我们还没出花园  笨蛋
We still haven't left the garden yet, silly.
-我害怕  -怕就不要跟来
-I'm scared.  -Shouldn't have come, then.
-说说话  -说什么?
-Say something.  -What shall I say?
不知道  说什么都行
I don't know. Anything.
我叫安  在走路
Let's see. My name is Anne and I'm walking.
在走路  我叫安
I'm walking and my name is Anne.
那里是什么?
What's that over there?
好像是墓地
I think they're graves.
不要过去!
Don't go near!
干嘛不?
Why not?
有鬼跳出来怎么办?
What if a ghost jumps out?
墓地没有鬼  只有骷髅
Graves don't have ghosts. Only skeletons.
上面有字
There's something written here.
走吧
Let's go!
等等
Wait!
"1891年12月"
安  写了什么?
Anne! What does it say?
"贝莎・米尔丝之墓 1829-1891"
你们要坚强些  孩子
You must be strong now, children.
尼古拉斯  快来!
Nicholas, come here!
米尔丝  别告诉妈妈我们出走
Mrs. Mills, please don't tell Mummy we've run away.
不要和他们说话!
Don't speak to them!
为什么?
Why?
-他们是死人!  -什么?
-They're dead!  -What?
他们是鬼!  快过来!
They're ghosts! Please come here!
孩子!
Children!
尼古拉斯!
Nicholas!
他们是鬼?
They're ghosts?
他们怎么没披白布戴锁链?
Why aren't they wearing sheets and clanking chains?
你曾说过的...
You said that...
别管我说过什么  快点跑!
I don't care what I said! Get away from them!
你老是唬弄我骗我
You're always teasing me and telling lies
我受够了
and I'm sick of it!
我没唬弄你  我说真的
I'm not teasing you! I'm telling the truth!
快过来!
Come here!
快!
Quick!
啊!  妈妈!  妈妈!
Aah! Mum! Mum!
孩子们!
Children!
快跑!
Run!
快跑!  跑进屋子!
Go! Into the house!
别再靠近!
Don't come any closer!
别动!
Don't move!
别再自寻烦恼了  太太
Don't trouble yourself, ma'am.
半个世纪前
Tuberculosis finished us off
我们都已死于肺结核
more than half a century ago.
滚开!
Go away!
太太  请开门
Open the door, ma'am, Please.
你们想干嘛?
What do you want?
妈妈  别开门
Mummy, don't open the door. Don't.
我们看见他们的坟墓
We've seen their graves.
躲到楼上去
Go upstairs and hide.
-快  -我害怕
-Go on.  -I'm scared.
-不要分开!  -噢
-Don't separate!  -Oh!
无论如何都不要分开
Whatever you do, don't separate.
躲起来  快点
Go hide. Go. Go.
我们一直试图使你明白
We've been trying to make you understand.
明白什么?
Understand what?
这间屋子
About the house.
和新的状况
About the new situation.
什么状况?
What situation?
我们必须学会和睦共处
We must all learn to live together,
活人和死人
the living and the dead.
你们死了就请放过我们
If you're dead, leave us in peace!
放过我们!
Oh. Leave us in peace!
Leave us in peace!
这里  进去
In here. Get inside.
就算我们放过你
And suppose we do leave you.
他们会放过吗?
Do you think they will?
谁?
Who?
不速之客
The intruders.
没有不速之客
There are no intruders.
窗帘是他们拆的
They took the curtains down.
我可以肯定就是他们
Oh, yes, I assure you it was them.
他们现在就与你和孩子一起
And now they're in there with you and the children.
等着你
Waiting for you.
不
No!
相信我  迟早
Yes. And believe me, sooner or later,
他们会找上你
they'll find you.
等在这里  我马上回来
Listen, wait here and I'll be back in a minute.
不  妈妈说了我们不分开
No, no, no. Mummy said we shouldn't separate.
我们不能留下她不管
We can't leave her on her own.
不要那样呼吸
Stop breathing like that.
尼古拉斯  别那样呼吸
Nicholas, stop breathing like that.
停止呼吸!
Stop breathing!
你没听见?  外面有人
Can't you hear it? There's someone there.
跟我来  孩子们
Come with us, children.
跟我来
Come with us.
尼古拉斯?
Nicholas?
安?
Anne?
你们在哪里?
Where are you?
回答我!
Answer me!
不速之客找到了他们
The intruders have found them.
我们无能为力了
There's nothing we can do now.
你只能上楼和他们谈谈
You'll have to go upstairs and talk to them.
我们的天父啊
Our Father, who art in Heaven
愿你的圣名显扬
hallowed be Thy name.
愿你的国度降临
Thy kingdom come.
我们将在人间奉行你的旨意
Thy will be done on earth
犹如在天堂
as it is in Heaven.
求你赐予我们每天的食粮
Give us this day our daily bread
求你原谅我们的罪过
and forgive us our trespasses.
你们怕什么?  孩子们
Why are you afraid, children?
我们不是朋友吗?
Why don't you want us to be your friends?
来吧  和我们说话
Come on, speak to us.
和我们说话
Speak to us.
告诉我发生了什么事
Tell me what happened.
不要说!  不要说!
Don't tell her! Don't tell her!
不要说
Don't tell her.
说了  他们就会放过我们
If I tell her, they'll leave us in peace.
妈咪!
Mummy!
Mummy.
你们为何哭?  孩子
Why are you crying, children?
这里发生什么事?
What happened in this room?
妈妈对你们做了什么?
What did your mother do to you?
好像是关于枕头
Something about a pillow.
她就是这样杀了你们?
Is that how she killed you?
用枕头?
With a pillow?
她没有杀我们
She didn't kill us!
孩子  你们死了
Children, if you're dead,
为什么还留在这屋里?
why do you remain in this house?
我们没死!
We're not dead!
为什么还留在这屋里?
Why do you remain in this house?
我们没死!
We're not dead!
为什么还留在这屋里?
Why do you remain in this house?
我们没死!  我们没死!
We're not dead. We're not dead.
我们没死!
We're not dead!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事  只是有点晕
Yes. Just a bit dizzy, that's all.
发生什么了?
What happened?
他们有通灵反应
They made contact.
三个都有?
All three?
一点没错
Apparently, yes.
母亲和两个孩子
The mother and the two children.
很有趣  是吧?
Quite interesting, don't you think?
有趣?
Interesting?
我吓得半死
I was scared out of my wits!
镇静些
Darling, calm down.
不  我们一直都听你的
No. So far, we have handled this matter your way,
现在轮到我做主
but now you listen to me.
我们不能再在这里住下去
We can't possibly stay in this house any longer.
很显然
It is quite clear
那些鬼魂不欢迎我们
that these beings do not want us to live here.
我们还未搞清楚
We don't know anything about them yet.
很清楚了
Yes, we do!
那个女人疯了
We know the woman went mad,
闷死了两个孩子后开枪自杀
smothered her two children, and then shot herself.
还不够清楚?  想想我们的儿子
That's quite enough. Think of our son.
维克多没什么事
There's nothing wrong with Victor.
有事!  他做噩梦
Yes, there is! He has nightmares.
说见到那女孩
He says he has seen that girl
还附上了这老妇人的身体
and even this lady has been possessed by her.
我们搬吧  离开这所房子
Please, let us leave this house.
好吧
All right.
明天一早就搬
We will leave tomorrow morning.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God for that.
我去看看维克多
I'll just go and check on Victor.
再次感谢你能来
Once again, thank you so much for coming.
不客气
A pleasure.
希望真的有所帮助
I hope we've been of some help.
当然  不过有点不太顺利
Oh, yes, of course. Though I must admit.
起初我不明白...
At first, I couldn't understand...
枕头怎么会在我手上
what the pillow was doing in my hands
为什么你们不动了?
or why you didn't move.
后来我知道了
But then I knew.
出了事
It had happened.
我杀了我的孩子
I had killed my children.
我拿起枪
I got the rifle.
对准自己额头
I put it to my forehead.
扣动了扳机
Then I pulled the trigger.
什么都没发生
Nothing.
随后我听见你们在睡房嬉笑
Then I heard your laughter in the bedroom.
你们在玩枕头
You were playing with the pillows
就像什么都没发生
as if nothing had happened.
我想慈悲的上帝
And I thought the Lord in his great mercy
给了我第二次机会
was giving me another chance,
告诉我  不要放弃
telling me, "Don't give up."
要努力
Be strong.
做孩子们的...
Be a good mother...
好妈妈
for them.
但现在
But now,
现在
now,
这都意味着什么?
what does all this mean?
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
丽蒂亚得知我们三个死去
Young Lydia said the very same thing
也问了同样的问题
when she realized the three of us were dead.
之后她就变哑了
And that was the last time she ever spoke.
我一直都不能告诉你
But I couldn't tell you that before now.
弄杯热茶喝吧  太太
Shall I make us a nice cup of tea, ma'am?
不速之客要走了
The intruders are leaving,
但新的还会来
but others will come.
有时我们会感觉到他们
Now, sometimes we'll sense them.
有时感觉不到
Other times, we won't.
从来就是如此
But that's the way it's always been.
太太
Ma'am.
妈咪
Mummy.
爸爸打仗死了  是吗?
Daddy died in the war, didn't he?
是的
Yes.
我们会再见到他吗?
Will we ever see him again?
不知道
I don't know.
如果我们死了  那边狱呢?
If we're dead, where's limbo?
我不知道边狱是否存在
I don't know if there even is a limbo.
我知道的不比你们多
I'm no wiser than you are,
我只知道我爱你们
but I do know that I love you.
一直都爱你们
I've always loved you.
这间屋子是我们的
And this house is ours.
一起跟我说
You say it with me.
这间屋子是我们的
This house is ours.
妈咪  看  没事的
Mummy, look. It doesn't hurt anymore.
没人能赶走我们
No one can make us leave this house.
走吧  维克多
Come along, Victor.
"出售"